Akanksha Arora

iOS Developer

Jersey City, NJ - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Akanksha-Arora/d0ca1d42a1a782ac

5+ years of extensive experience in Mobile application development

Proficiency in Objective C and Cocoa experience

Proficiency in UIKit, Foundation, Core Animation and Core Graphics

Proficiency in Debugging, troubleshooting and iOS memory management.

Hands on experience of iOS programming features like Auto Layout, StoryBoards, NSOperation/NSOperation

Queues, Blocks, GCD, Protocols, Delegate, NSNotificationCenter etc

Knowledge of Core Data, XML parsing, Multithreading, MapKit and APNS

Experience with Javascript, jQuery, NodeJS, Grunt and HTML5 technologies

Experience in complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Agile Methodologies (Scrum).

Experience with source control tools like SVN and JIRA.

Beginner level knowledge of Swift

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

iOS

Verizon Wireless - Cellular & More - Township of Warren, NJ - November 2016 to February 2017

mPOS application is an iOS application developed for sales representatives. It is an enterprise-based application. This application helps sales representative to assist customers on different plans, data packages and device plans available. This app keeps track of all plans and lines provided to a customer as well as the offers eligible. It provides an interface for the representatives to manage or shop devices and plans.

Responsibilities

Created the front-end UI design of the app using UIKit framework primarily, including UITabBarController, UITableView Collection,UINavigationController and Using AutoLayout and NSLayoutConstraint to create proper UI.

Used MVC and VIPER design pattern, protocols and delegates to design the application's architecture

Used UINavigationController, segue and Delegate designed user interface

Use UICollectionView for presenting available devices and utilize UICollection-Delegate and UICollectionLayoutDelegate to implement customized requirements

Dynamically updated the UITableview with the JSON data and show the user new events

Using UIRefresh Control to refresh and reload UICollectionView Data

Used core data for data storage

Following Model, View and Controller paradigm by handling the view frames of all UI components in view controller itself

Involved in creating application-compatibility in both portrait, landscape modes for iPad by making use of Auto-Sizing constraints

Participated in application testing using in Objective C framework and fixed them thereby contributing for application enhancement

Took care of code review code fixes and bug fixes

Involved in the requirement gathering, project plan, effort estimations leading to successful product delivery

Analyst

Magic Software Inc - September 2010 to November 2015

Sep 2010 - Oct 2015

Worked on variety of iOS apps ranging from interactive games, eTextBook app for iPad and Mac OS X, XAPI and Easy XDM frameworks based Activity apps and real-time classroom polling apps

Architected education game engine to deliver highly interactive education games for iPhone and iPad Worked with global publishers including Turning Technologies, Houghton Mifflin, TCM and The Lakeshore Learning.

Worked on HTML5 and JS based web projects

Software Developer

Hurix Pvt. Ltd. - Mumbai, Maharashtra - April 2010 to September 2010

Responsibilities

Worked as a software developer on Adobe Flash and Flex technologies

EDUCATION

MCA in Computer Science

Banasthali Vidyapith - Rajasthan 2006 to 2009

SKILLS

Objective-C (3 years), Swift (Less than 1 year), Javascript, HTML5 (Less than 1 year), Flash, action script 3.0 (2 years)

AWARDS

WOW Award

September 2015

It was given for the excellent performance on the eTextBook Application.

Star Performer

July 2012

It was given for the performance in the Turning Technology Application.